Guide to the Beth El Synagogue Records, 1881-2012 and undated RL.11336
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1900-2004; undated; 3
  - Beth-El photographs from Maxine Stern, 2010-2011; 1 CD containing 75 files; 57.3 MB. (Box 25, Digital-materials RL11336-SET-0001)
    Photograph files of people at gatherings and events in JPEG format.
  - Beth-El Preschool and Hebrew School, 1995-2002; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Beth-El Preschool and Hebrew School, 1995-2002; undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Beth-El Presidents, undated (Box 13)
  - Beth-El Renovations, undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
    Photographs by Levinsohn, Hunter
  - Biloxi, 2007 March 7; 1 CD containing 69 files; 196 MB. (Box 25, Digital-materials RL11336-SET-0001)
    Photographs of service projects that include making food and building a house. Images are in JPEG format.
  - Building and Renovations, 1999 (Box 13)
  - Cemetary, undated (Box 13)
  - Chanukah Bazaar, 1999 (Box 13)
  - Children painting, undated (Box 13)
  - Congregation Photo, undated (Box 24)
  - Early Durham Hebrew Congregation, undated (Box 13)
  - For Temple Bulletin Board Displays, 1983; undated; 3 folders (Box 13)
    Congregation members involved in various activities at the synagogue
  - Freedman Center, 1988 (Box 13)
    Construction photographs
  - Gladsteins Store Photograph, 1900 (Box 13)
    Main Street, Durham, NC; contains correspondence regarding photograph
  - Bruce Guild and Linda Convissor Wedding, 1983 (Box 14)
  - Judaica, 2004 (Box 25, Digital-materials RL11336-SET-0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    3.5 floppy disc containing 23 files; less than 1 MB.
    Includes photographs taken on a Mavica camera of Judaica in JPG format; there is 1 file in HTML format.
  - Living Heritage: Jewish Ceremonial Art, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Photograph Collages, undated (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Paper Prints, 2004 (Box 14)
    Photograph order forms
  - Miscellaneous Negatives, undated (Box 14)
  - Photographs Not Used in Photo Album, undated (Box 14)
    Unused photographs from synagogue photograph album; various congregation activities
  - A Photographic History of Beth-El, 1984-1987; undated (Box 14)
    Contents of photgraph album
  - Pictures From Photo Directory, undated (Box 14)
  - Pictures of Rabbi Foger and Synagogue Interior, 1987 (Box 14)
  - Portrait of Rabbi Steven Sagar, undated (Box 14)
  - Portraits of Members, 1965; undated (Box 14)
  - Purim Carnival and Shabbaton, 1987-1997; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Bar Mitzvah for Stern, Sam and Bat Mitzvah for Stern, Becky, undated; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - "Rabbi's 25th" photographs from Lauren Quigley, 2004; 1 CD containing 120 files; 85 MB. (Box 25, Digital-materials RL11336-SET-0001)
    120 photograph files in JPEG format.
  - Sefer Torah, 1988 (Box 15)
  - Shabbaton, 1984-1998; 6 folders (Box 15)
  - Beth-El Sisterhood Photographs, undated (Box 15)
  - Slides from Various Synagogue Events, undated (Box 15)
  - Synagogue Play, 1964 (Box 15)
    Cast photograph; play title unknown
  - Synagogue Events, 1965-1994; 4 folders (Box 15)
    Congregation members at various events and synagogue activities
  - Synagogue Events, 1983-2004; undated; 10 folders (Box 16)
  - Synagogue Events, undated; 12 folders (Box 17)
  - Worship Conductors, 1997 (Box 17)
  - Uncaptioned Photo Albums, 1984-2001; undated; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Photographs: Mitzvah Project, 2001 January (Box 29)
- Printed Materials, 1909-2012; undated; 4
  Printed Materials include newspaper clippings from throughout the twentieth century, primarily from the Durham Morning Herald, that pertain to the synagogue, its members, or Jewish life. Includes ephemera from the funeral for the first Jewish mayor of Durham, "Mutt" Evans. The series also contains a book printed in Hebrew, Sidur u-Mahzor, Kol-Bo. The text is the second part of a set of prayer books that include daily prayers, prayers for high holidays such as Rosh Ha-shanah and Yom Kippur, liturgical poems, and the psalms, among others. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - The American Jewish Times Outlook, 1986-1987 (Box 18)
  - Book of Songs and Blessings, 1983 (Box 18)
    United Jewish Appeal
  - Calendar, 1975 (Box 18)
  - Centennial Celebration, 1987-1988 (Box 18)
    Newspaper Clippings
  - Featuring Beth-El Members, 1996-1997; undated (Box 18)
  - Jewish Art and Culture in Early America, 1981 (Box 18)
    By Spoleto, Piccolo
  - Jewish Burial, 1991 (Box 18)
    Newspaper clippings
  - Jewish Year Programs, undated (Box 18)
    Handbooks on Jewish religious events
  - Judaism and the Environment, 2004-2008; 2 CDs containing 229 files; 4.35 GB. (Box 25, Digital-materials RL11336-SET-0001)
    2-disc CD set on "supporting environmental education and activism in conservative/Masorti communities". Document, photograph, and video files are in JPEG, PDF, MS Powerpoint PPS, HTML, CSS, MPEG-2, and VOB formats.
  - Emmanuel "Mutt" Evans Funeral, 1997 (Box 18)
    Newspapers, photograph
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1971-2004 (Box 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1959-1961 (Box 18)
    Beth-El Sisterhood
  - Newspaper Clippings Obituaries, 1985-1986; undated (Box 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1909-2012; undated; 4 folders (Box 19)
    Durham Morning Herald, Durham Herald
  - Our Synagogue, 1974 (Box 19)
  - Rabbis Newspaper Clippings, 1958; undated (Box 19)
  - A Set of Holiday Sermons, 1961-1962 (Box 19)
    Union of American Hebrew Congregations
  - Southern Jewish Historical Society, 1983-1987 (Box 19)
    Newsletters, pamphlets
  - Hebrew prayer book, 1923 (Box 28)
    In Hebrew: Sidur Mahazor Kol-bo, second part. Published in Vilna, 1923.
  - Miscellaneous Materials, 1972-1986 (Box 29)
  - Adult Jewish Education, approximately 1959 (Box 29)
- Programming, 1899-2007; undated; 5
  Programming includes copies of the synagogue's newsletter, the Beth El Bulletin, assorted service bulletins, and a dedication book to commemorate the construction of the new synagogue on Markham and Watts Streets in Durham. Also includes welcome booklets, and miscellaneous handouts and programs. Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Annual Yearbook, 1959-1960 (Box 19)
    Beth-El congregation
  - Beth-El Bulletin, 1955-1979; 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Beth-El Bulletin, 1987-2006; undated; 9 folders (Box 20)
  - Beth-El Welcome Booklets, undated (Box 20)
  - A Dedication to the Future, 1960 (Box 21)
    Synagogue dedication book
  - A Dedication to the Future Drafts and Proofs, 1959-1960; 2 folders (Box 21)
    Drafts and proofs of dedication book
  - Miscellaneous Programs, 1899-1960 (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous Handouts, undated (Box 21)
  - Remembrance Books, 1986; 1997 (Box 21)
    Evans, Emanuel Joshua "Mutt"; Evans, Sara Nachamson
  - Service Bulletins, 1948-1978; 3 folders (Box 21)
    Programs from assorted temple services
  - Service Bulletins, 1979-1988; undated; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Service Invitations, 1965-2007 (Box 22)
  - Yom Kippur Memorial Books, 1988; 2006 (Box 22)
  - Josah Luncheon and Purim Show Report, 1957-1960 (Box 29)